A Guide to the Owen B. Pickett Pre-Congressional Papers, 1955-1988
Library of Virginia
- Campaign Files 1967-1986
  This series contains files relating to campaigns on the local, state, and national level. Includes files from campaigns in which Pickett ran for office and others in which he was actively involved, and files from his service as Chairman of the Virginia Beach Democratic Committee, Second District Democratic Committee, and Democratic State Central Committee. Includes material from the 1967 Virginia Beach Democratic Primary between the Kellam Machine (Administration Team) and the United Candidates, Pickett's election and re-election campaigns for the House of Delegates in 1971, 1973, 1975, 1977, 1979, 1981, 1982, 1983, and 1985 (Due to redistricting, the General Assembly members elected in 1981 had to run again in 1982, but in single member districts. Pickett defeated Melvin Spence to represent the 81st District in the House of Delegates), and a few files from the 1986 Congressional Campaign. These campaign files include advertisements, contact lists, expenditure reports, fundraising information, invoices and receipts for advertising, and research on opponents' voting records.
  - Campaign 1967 (Box 15)
  - Campaign, 1967 - Clippings, Mar. - Aug. 1967, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
  - Election, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 5-8)
  - Campaign, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 9-12)
  - Campaign, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
  - Campaign, 1975 - Advertisement Photographs (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1977 - Re-election material (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Campaign, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Campaign, 1979 - Poll workers (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 10-12)
  - Campaign Poll Workers Information, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Finance Campaign Information, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic House of Delegates Race, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Correspondence, 1 Sept. - 30 Nov. 1982 (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Correspondence re. Campaign Contributions, 30 Aug. 1982 - 3 Jan. 1983 (Box 17, Folder 8-11)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 12-14)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Finance Information (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Notebook (I) (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Notebook (II) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Petitions (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Precinct Information (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Voting on legislation which increased taxes, licenses, or fees (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Weekly Patron Reports - Pickett, 1972-1986 (Box 18, Folder 5-8)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1982 - Weekly Patron Reports - Melvin Spence, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1983 - Petitions (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1985 - Campaign contributions and Expenditure report (includes clippings on possible Pickett bid for Lt. Governor in 1985) (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1985 - Petitions (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - United States Senate Campaign, 1982 - Bumper stickers (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - United States Senate Campaign, 1982 - Fundraiser, 10 Apr. 1982 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - United States Senate Campaign, 1982 - Statement and clippings (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Letter of support from Gerald L. Baliles (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Letters of support and clippings (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - PAC Letter (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Committee Voting Record for Owen Pickett, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Lists of House Bills, Senate Bills, and Resolutions, 1972-1986 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Bills on which Owen Pickett was patron/co-patron and others, 1972-1980 (Box 19, Folder 9-17)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Bills on which Owen Pickett was patron/co-patron and others, 1981-1986 (Box 20, Folder 1-5)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Notes on A. Joe Canada's Legislative Activities (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Campaign, 1986 - Bills on which A. Joe Canada Jr. was patron/co-patron, 1972-1985 (Box 20, Folder 7-13)
  - Norfolk Listings, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Beach Listings, 1980-1985 (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
  - Virginia Beach Precincts Record, 1981-1984 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Beach City Council Elections, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic Committee - Fundraiser, Virginia Beach Democratic Candidates, 13 Sept. 1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic Committee - Virginia Beach Democratic Campaign Planning Committee, 1980-1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic Campaign Planning Committee, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Beach Democratic Women's Club, 1979-1987 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Second District Democratic Committee, 1976 - 1976 Democratic National Convention (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Second District Democratic Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Second District Democratic Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - State Democratic Convention, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 16-18)
  - State Democratic Convention, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
  - Selection of State Party Chairman, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia, 1981 - Chairman Files (Box 22, Folder 5-10)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia, 1981-1982 - Chairman Files (Box 22, Folder 11-13)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Baliles Campaign for Attorney General, 1980-1981 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Campaign Fundraising Information - July 17th Cavalier Fundraiser, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Campaign Fundraising Information - Democratic State Fundraisers, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising Information (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Media Information (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Women, 1984 (Lynn Fischer and Eva Teig) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Mondale for President, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Geraldine Ferraro Information(clippings), 1984 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Republican News Letters, 1980-1983 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - National Election Results, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Advertisements - Owen B. Pickett (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Advertisements - (President, U. S. Senate, U. S. House of Representatives), 1976-1978 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Advertisements - (Governor, Lt. Governor, Attorney General), 1977 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Advertisements - (General Assembly), 1977 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Notebook re. 1981 House of Delegates Re-election Campaign, 1981 Gubernatorial election, and 1982 U. S. Senate Campaign, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 14-16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1977, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 17)
- Legislative Files, 1971-1986
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972, 1976-1978, 1984-1986
    Includes correspondence, arranged in reverse chronological order, to and from constituents and General Assembly colleagues regarding legislative proposals, issues, and bills. Interspersed among the correspondence are letters relating to campaigns, elections, and Democratic Party business.
    - Correspondence, Mar. - Aug. 1971 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Sept. - Oct. 1971 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2-10 Nov. 1971 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 11-30 Nov. 1971 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Dec. 1971 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Jan. - Apr. 1972 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Apr. - June 1976 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, July 1976 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 2-9 Aug. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 10-28 Aug. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Sept. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Oct. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Nov. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 2-14 Dec. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 15-31 Dec. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 3-13 Jan. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 17-31 Jan. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Feb. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1-20 Mar. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 21-31 Mar. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1-6 Apr. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 11-15 Apr. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 18-29 Apr. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 2-10 May 1977 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 11-19 May 1977 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 20-31 May 1977 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, June 1977 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, July 1977 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Aug. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1-18 Sept. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 19-30 Sept. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 3-13 Oct. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 21-31 Oct. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1-22 Nov. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 23-30 Nov. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 5-13 Dec. 1977 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 14-21 Dec. 1977 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 22-30 Dec. 1977 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 3-13 Jan. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 14-31 Jan. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1-8 Feb. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 9-28 Feb. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1-16 Mar. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 20-28 Mar. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1-11 Apr. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 14-27 Apr. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1-18 May 1978 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 19-31 May 1978 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1-12 June 1978 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 3-5 July 1978 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 7 July - 1 Aug. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, June 1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 3-11 July 1984 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 12-31 July 1984 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 5-14 Aug. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 16-31 Aug. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 4-13 Sept. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 14-28 Sept. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1-11 Oct. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 15-18 Oct. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 19-26 Oct. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 26-31 Oct. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1-15 Nov. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 6-11 Nov. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 12-30 Nov. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 3-10 Dec. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 11-17 Dec. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 20-31 Dec. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1-3 Jan. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 4-9 Jan. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 15-29 Jan. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Feb. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1-14 Mar. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 15-29 Mar. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1-26 Apr. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, May 1985 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, June 1985 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, July 1985 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Aug. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Sept. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1-14 Oct. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 15-30 Oct. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Nov. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 4-16 Dec. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 16-31 Dec. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Jan. 1986 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Feb. 1986 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 3-18 Mar. 1986 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 19-31 Mar. 1986 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Subject Files, 1971-1986
    Arranged alphabetically, this subseries contains material relating to legislation introduced in the General Assembly and constituent mail supporting or opposing the legislation. Includes files on abortion, Camp Pendleton, education, Equal Rights Amendment, False Cape State Park, social services, Virginia Beach, and the Virginia Supplemental Retirement System, among other. Also includes opinions of Virginia's Attorney General on various issues, page and aide applications and letters, press releases and speeches, voter surveys, and questionnaires and polls.
    - Abortion - Memorialization Bill (H.J.R. 219), 1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Alcohol and Drug Abuse Publications, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Animal Legislation, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Attorney General Opinions, 12 June 1973 - 11 Nov. 1977 (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
    - Attorney General Opinions, 1980-1985 (Box 29, Folder 10-15)
    - Bills, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Biography and Committee Assignments (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Board of Governors - Health Law Section, 2 July 1984 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Budget, 1977 Session (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Camp Pendleton Transaction, 1971-1975 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Census Subcommittee, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
    - Christmas Card List, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Collective Bargaining for Public Employees, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Conflict of Interest - "Private Profit, Public Trust" (reprinted from Norfolk Virginian-Pilot, 6-10 Jan. 1980) (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Coordination of Health Benefits, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Cranwell (Richard) Legislation (H.B. 276 and H.B. 566), 1978 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Credit Card Phone Charges - House of Delegates, 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Disable Veteran Legislation, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Distribution of Sales Tax Formula, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Education - Elementary and Secondary, 1976-1978 (Box 30, Folder 13-14)
    - Equal Rights Amendment (I), 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Equal Rights Amendment (II-III), 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - False Cape State Park - Access Route, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - False Cape State Park, 1979-1982 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Follow up, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Gifted Student, 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Addresses - Mills E. Godwin, 12 Jan. 1977; John N. Dalton, 14 Jan. 1981 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Haygood Legislation Office, Listing of Materials In (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hospitals, Medicare, Nursing, Child Care (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - House Resolutions and House Joint Resolutions, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - How a Bill Becomes a Law, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Jamestown - Yorktown Foundation - Minutes, 13 May 1986 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Judicial System, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Juveniles, 1976-1978 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Lake Gaston Pipeline, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Landscape Architecture (H.B. 733), 1977 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Legislation patroned/co-patroned by Owen B. Pickett, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Legislation patroned/co-patroned by Owen B. Pickett, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Legislation patroned/co-patroned by Glen McClanan, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Legislation patroned/co-patroned by Owen B. Pickett, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Legislation suggested by the City of Virginia Beach, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Legislation, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Legislation, Final Reports on, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Letters - Various bills, 1977 General Assembly Session (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Nansemond Indian Tribe - Oliver L. Perry, 1984-1993 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Natural Death Act (H.B. 1840), 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Optometrists - Drugs, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Page Applications and Form Letter (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Page/Aide Applications and Letters, 4 Oct. 1978 - 1986 (Box 32, Folder 9-14)
    - Pendleton Project, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Prepayment of Loans, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases and Speech Materials (includes campaign material), 1979-1982 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Proposed Legislation, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Public Facilities Bond Act of 1977 (H.B. 1978), 1977 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
    - Questionnaires and Polls, 1976-1984 (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
    - Questionnaires and Polls - National Right to Work Committee, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Retirement Subcommittee, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Robb, Charles S., 1982 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - School Nurses (H.B. 945), 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Self-Employed Watermen, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Senate Resolutions and Senate Joint Resolutions, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Social Services (I), 1979-1984 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Social Services (II-III), 1979-1984 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
    - Southern Growth Policies Board - Welfare Reform, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Sunset Legislation, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Survey Responses, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Thank yous, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Beach, 1980-1984 (Box 34, Folder 7-10)
    - Virginia Beach - Boards and Commissions, and Legislators (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Beach - Council and City Information, 1982-1984 (Box 34, Folder 12-13)
    - Virginia Beach Legislative Proposals, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Beach - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, 1979-1984 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Coordinate System (Virginia Polytechnic Institute), 1976 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Virginians for Bonds, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Oceanographic Museum, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Supplemental Retirement System, 1977-1978 (Box 35, Folder 3-9)
    - (Box 35)
- Clippings and Scrapbooks, 1966-1988
  Includes newspaper clippings and scrapbooks relating to Pickett's legislative and political career. The majority of these clippings are from the Virginia Beach Beacon, Virginia Beach Sun, Norfolk Virginian- Pilot, Richmond News Leader, and Richmond Times-Dispatch. Of note are the clippings from the 1985 General Assembly session.
  - Clippings (elections and campaigns), 1966-1982, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (legislative matters and miscellaneous), 1967-1979, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Oct. 1981, May - Nov. 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Clippings - 1985 General Assembly, 16 Sept. 1984 - 24 Feb. 1985 (Box 36, Folder 2-8)
  - Clippings - U. S. Congress, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 9-11)
  - Scrapbook (clippings re. campaigns and legislative matters), 1 Nov. 1979 - 23 Nov. 1986 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook (photocopies) (I-IV), 18 Mar. 1982 - 7 Jan. 1987 (Box 36, Folder 13-16)
  - Scrapbook (photocopies) (V), 18 Mar. 1982 - 7 Jan. 1987 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook (original), 18 Mar. 1982 - 7 Jan. 1987 (Box 37, Folder 2-6)
- Legal Files, 1983-1985
  This series contains billing records from Pickett's law firm for legal work performed.
  - Billing Records, 6 Jan. 1983 - 28 Feb. 1985 (Box 37, Folder 7-13)
  - Billing Records, 1 Mar. - 31 Dec. 1985 (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
- University of Richmond Law School Personal Notes
  Includes fifteen bound notebooks containing notes from various law classes taken at the University of Richmond T. C. Williams School of Law.
  - General (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - General (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Agency and Partnership; Administrative Law (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Constitutional Law (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Contracts (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Law (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Domestic Relations (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Federal Estate and Gift Taxation (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Federal Procedure (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Labor Law (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Property (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Remedies (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Taxation (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Trusts (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Wills and Administration (Box 40, Folder 5)
- Schedule Books, 1955-1987
  This series consists of schedule books breaking down Pickett's daily activities for the years from 1955 to 1987. Also includes pocket diaries.
  - 1955 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - 1957 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - 1958 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - 1960 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - 1963 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - 1964 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - 1965 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - 1969 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 1970 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - 1971 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - 1972 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - 1973 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - 1974 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - 1975 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - 1976 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - 1977 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - 1978 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - 1979 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 1980 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - 1981 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - 1982 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - 1983 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - 1984 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - 1985 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - 1986 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - 1987 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Pocket Diaries, 1961-1962 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Diaries, 1966-1968 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Pocket Diaries, 1969-1972 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Diaries, 1973-1978 (Box 46)
  - Pocket Diaries, 1979-1986 (Box 46)